UDAY KUMAR VURUKONDA

Fitchburg, MA 04210 | 201-993-5681 | udaykumar6273@gmail.com | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

A passionate individual with 3 years of work experience as a Full Stack Developer with strong C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, PowerShell, Angular, and excellent debugging skills. Eager to learn and develop large-scale software in an agile environment and create a positive impact on lives.

EDUCATION

Fitchburg State University | Master of Science (MS) in Computer Science

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech)

Sep 2013- May 2017

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Databases Management Systems | Mobile and Web Technologies Development | Business Intelligence | Embedded Systems | Computer Networking | Data Structures and Algorithms | Distributed Computing Theories | Wireless & Satellite Communication | Relational Database | TCP / IP Protocols | UDP | Linear Algebra | Control Systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, .Net, Java 8, Auto IT, OOP, Angular JS, React, Verilog, bootstrap, Node.js

Database Management: MYSQL, AWS, SQL Server DB

Operating Systems: Windows 7 and 10, Linux, Real Time Operating System.

Web Application Frameworks: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, PHP

Work Management Tool: Agile, Waterfall, JIRA, Scrum-Kanban, TDD

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Tech Mahindra Hyderabad, India

Senior Software Engineer Feb 2021 – Apr 2021

- Designed and Developed Web application using AngularJS for frontend and Asp.Net Web API for backend.
- Analyzed the data, designed GUIs with JSP, JavaScript, Html & CSS and debugged code which increased the code efficiency by 30%.
- Designed and setup CI/CD pipeline to deploy containerized applications in the cloud.
- Understanding and modifying Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC requirements, design, development, unit testing, deployment, and version control), Updating, requirement analysis, functional/design specifications, Test plans designing.

Software Engineer Feb 2019 – Nov 2021

- Developed various Windows desktop APIs and User Experience applications using C#, JavaScript, WinForms, and ASP.NET.
- Coded various Shell scripts to automate backup and recovery.
- Implemented multiple CI/CD pipelines as part of DevOps role for us on-premises and cloud-based software using Jenkins, Chef and AWS.
- Wrote REST APIs in java to support internalization, and apps to help our buyer team visualize, set portfolio performance targets.
- Created a dynamic and automated inventory of workstation software/hardware on the network PowerShell scripting and WMI.
- Extensively used Auto IT Shell Scripts for automating batch programs.
- Integrated jenkins with aws plugin so that the jenkins slaves are online only when called, resulting in cost savings to the customer.

Associate Software Engineer

Apr 2018 - Jan 2019

- Utilized Jenkins, Git, and Eclipse for deployment on test servers and to move towards CI/CD. Developed various Windows desktop APIs and User Experience applications using C#, JavaScript, WinForms, and ASP.NET.
- Performed TestNG and Selenium Testing on an application that was in the development phase.
- Performed RESTful API Testing (using GET, POST, PUT, DELETE HTTP Methods) using the REST.
- Written efficient Java code and SQL queries to achieve the desired result of distributed concurrency.
- Used JIRA to keep track of outstanding bugs to reduce downtime, increase productivity, and improve communication.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Timesheet Management System

Online Mobile Recharge

ATM Banking System

E-Commerce Website

E Health Care Management System

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Visual Studio MySQL, Google Analytics, Android Studio, RESTful API, MATLAB, Oracle VM VirtualBox, IOT, Arduino IDE - Arduino Uno R3, java, Azure Web Services, MS Office, Bash, AWS, REST, Google Cloud, Power Shell, SharePoint, Rest, Git, cloud, UI.

Activities: Dancing, Critical thinking, Responsive, Creatively, Innovation, Leadership Collaborator, Client-driven individual

Transferable Skills: Motivated, ability to Collaborate, Curious, Flexible to work, Strong analytical and problem solving.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Gold Medal in 12th Standard for Outstanding performance in Physics and Mathematics.

Awarded \$6000 scholarship from Seidenberg School Of Computer Science and Information Systems | Pace University